# Samuel Pettyjohn

Allen, TX, 903.216.7606, Sammpj47@gmail.com

### PROFILE

Procurement Specialist with over eight years of experience in providing proactive Supply Chain and Logistic support in the healthcare, retail, and manufacturing sectors. Insuring that the best interests of the organization are upheld by exercising industry-best practices and applying focused, value-added solutions.

#### **EDUCATION**

Jan 2015 — Dec 2019

# Bachelor's of Science in Business Operations, University of Texas

Tyler

Coursework: Operations Management, Supply Chain & Logistics, Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP).

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Mar 2021 — Present

## Buyer, UT Southwestern Medical Center

- Receives and reviews complex requisitions; applies appropriate procurement procedures; solicits
  telephone, electronic and written bids; analyzes bids/proposals across vendors, develops specifications and
  issues purchase orders following established processes.
- Accesses PeopleSoft Purchasing System to process department requisitions and inquire into accounting and receiving systems to track status of purchase orders.
- Communicate with vendors to resolve discrepancies between purchase orders and invoices and/or
  problems involving delivery dates, O/S/D, incorrect merchandise, incomplete orders, non-deliveries,
  rejection status inquiries to satisfaction of involved parties. Review and request status inquiries from
  receiving and accounting. Review and amend PO's accordingly in reference to Match Exceptions,
  communicating changes to appropriate personnel.
- Develops in-depth knowledge of, and procurement expertise in, designated procurement areas in order to
  function as specialist in area of procurement. Assists with preparation of invitations for bid and or submits
  request for proposal solicitation packages. Completes commercial/pricing evaluations of bid or proposal
  responses.
- Contacts, advises, and/or assists personnel of own or other departments with respect to requisitions, delivery dates, sole justifications, specifications, substitutions, and supply sources concerning any aspect of purchase orders or request for bid/proposals, originated by incumbent.

# Sep 2018 — Jan 2021

### Senior Purchasing Agent, Winn Consulting & Services

- Perform Procure to Pay Processes (P2P): create inquiries and requisitions for materials. Prepare Purchase
   Orders from approved requisitions received from vendors. Accurately review and process invoices.
- Review contracts and material costs for negotiation, resulting in savings over \$750,000.
- Collaborate with manufacturing and warehouse to track and manage inventory levels, maintaining a 100% on-time schedule and order fulfillment rate.
- Communicate closely with cross-functional teams to secure a durable procurement plan.
- Evaluate vendors based on price, quality, availability, reliability and support.
- Support financial and performance risk identification and analysis for suppliers.
- · Participate in weekly Schedule Control meetings.

# Sep 2015 — Sep 2018

### Operations Planner, Landstar Systems

- Worked with warehouses, brokers, and direct customers to successfully ensure facilitation of freight.
- Reduced lane costs by an average of 24% (YoY) through negotiating contract terms with 3PL carriers.
- Maintained 100% Safety FMCSA rating by ensuring compliance with all DOT regulations and laws.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Purchasing: Procure to Pay Process, Invitation for Bids, Request for Quotation, Commodity Codes, Invoice Processing, Negotiation

Technologies: PeopleSoft 9.2, Quickbooks Enterprise, EDI, JAGGAER, Microsoft Office Suite, Microsoft Teams